Guide to the Acton Visual Materials at La Pietra MSS.LaPietra.001
Villa La Pietra
- Series V: Places
  - Subseries A: Italian Villas and Gardens
    - 2 Italy
      - Pallanza (Lago Maggiore): Villa San Remigio (owned by Marchese della Valle di Casanova), undated; cuid4017 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Pernumia (province of Padova): Villa Maldura Bonacossi, undated; cuid4018 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Porto Potenza Picena (province of Macerata): Villa Buonaccorsi (Castel San Filippo), undated; cuid4019 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Ravello (Salerno): Villa Cimbrone, undated; cuid4020 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Ravello (Salerno): Palazzo Rufolo, undated; cuid4021 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Roma: Villa Albani, undated; cuid4022 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Roma: Villa Borghese, undated; cuid4023 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        1. photo (postcard size) by Anderson, 440. 2-4. [photos by Brogi, 6190, 6189, 4779.)], 5. photo by Alinari, 6797.
      - Roma: Villa Borghese, undated; cuid4024 (Box Oversize, Folder 338)
        Photo by R. Moscioni, Roma, 1659. Oversize, V.A.2.2. folder 338.
      - Roma: Villa Colonna, undated; cuid4025 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Roma: Villa Doria Pamphilj, undated; cuid4026 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        #2. Photo by Brogi, 8032.
      - Roma: Villa Giulia, undated; cuid4027 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        Photo by Brogi, 8866.
      - Roma: Villa Madama, undated; cuid4028 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        Photo by R. Moscioni, 9457.
      - Roma: Villa Medici, undated; cuid4029 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Roma: Villa Sciarra (owned by George W. Wurts), undated; cuid4030 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Tivoli (province of Roma): Villa d'Este, undated; cuid4031 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Tivoli (province of Roma): Villa d'Este, undated; cuid4032 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        #2. photo by Anderson, 4689. Photo by Moscioni, Roma, 15344.
      - Tivoli (province of Roma): Villa d'Este, undated; cuid4033 (Box Oversize, Folder 339)
        Oversize, V.A.2.2. folder 339.
      - Valsanzibio (province of Padova): Villa Barbarigo (Donà delle Rose), ca. 1911-1919; cuid4034 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Vicenza, Villa Rotonda, undated; cuid4035 (Box 2, Folder 41)
        Photo by Otto Schmidt, Wien, 3340.
    - 3 unidentified
      - [Firenze] Limonaia and grand garden entrance, undated; cuid4036 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - [Firenze, Villa I Collazzi], undated; cuid4037 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - [Farinola], undated; cuid4038 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - [Valsanzibio (province of Padova) Villa Barbarigo (Donà delle Rose)], undated; cuid4039 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Villa near Abano Terme (province of Padova), undated; cuid4040 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - [Villa in the province of Siena], undated; cuid4041 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Villa near Napoli, 1916; cuid4042 (Box 2, Folder 48)
        Taken on an Acton family trip, 1916, annotated on the verso by HMA.
      - [Villa near Pesaro], undated; cuid4043 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Unidentified villas and gardens (including grottoes, fountains, statues, and garden follies), undated; cuid4044 (Box 2, Folder 50-62a.)
      - [Villa in Sicilia] [Castello di Poppi, Casentino, province of Arezzo], undated; cuid4045 (Box 2, Folder 63-65.)
      - Garden fountain and garden gate, undated; cuid4046 (Box 2, Folder 66-67.)
      - Garden grotto, undated; cuid4047 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Castle courtyard: [a Bardini property: Torre del Gallo or Marignolle, Firenze ], ca. 1908; cuid4048 (Box 2, Folder 69)
        Neg. See also V.A.3.2.70.
      - Castle: [a Bardini property: Torre del Gallo or Marignolle, Firenze ], ca. 1910; cuid4049 (Box 2, Folder 70)
        Neg. and prints. See also V.A.3.2.69. Exteriors, interiors and the courtyard.
      - Villa garden with a copy of Giambologna's statue of Mercury, undated; cuid4050 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Villa garden, ca. 1912; cuid4051 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Villa garden, undated; cuid4052 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - Garden grotto, undated; cuid4053 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Venetian villa, undated; cuid4054 (Box 2, Folder 75)
        1.and 2. exteriors.
        3. courtyard.
        4. interior, annotated on the verso by AA "One of a series of Columns of rare marbles in a ruined Venetian villa".
        5. and 6. interiors (with columns.
      - Statue in a garden, undated; cuid4055 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Fountain in a garden, undated; cuid4056 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Statue of a Colossus in a villa courtyard [Villa Maser], undated; cuid4057 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Villa garden, undated; cuid4058 (Box 2, Folder 79)
      - Exterior of a villa with circular outside stairs and a clock and heraldic device on the façade (with a group of four people), undated; cuid4059 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      - Garden in a [convent] courtyard, undated; cuid4060 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Villa garden terrace with a fountain and statues, undated; cuid4061 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Hillside with villas and a barn (fienile) [near Firenze], undated; cuid4062 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Villa piscina (fountain) with four statues on the wall, undated; cuid4063 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Subseries B: Exteriors
    - 1 Firenze
      - Views of Firenze, undated; cuid4064 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Detail of the fountain in Piazza della Signoria, undated; cuid4065 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        Photo by Gorsen, annotated on the verso.
      - British pavilion at the fair in the Parco delle Cascine, 1918, cuid4066 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - A terrace overlooking the Arno, undated; cuid4067 (Box Oversize, Folder 340)
        Oversize, V.B.1.3. folder 340.
      - Houses on the Arno [before their destruction in the Second World War], 1918; cuid4068 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        Annotated on the verso by HMA "Sensani's apartment, 1918" [G.C. Sensani]
      - Badia Fiesolana, undated; cuid4069 (Box 3, Folder 5)
        #2. photo by Brogi, 9814.
      - Fiesole [with HMA and an officer], 1915; cuid4070 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - The Arno in flood, November 4, 1966; cuid4071 (Box Oversize, Folder 341)
        Photo signed by Balthazar Korab.
        Oversize, V.B.1.3. folder 341.
      - [San Martino alle Palme], undated; cuid4072 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 2 Italy
      - Amalfi, undated; cuid4073 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Asciano (province of Siena), Centro Studi Amos Cassioli, undated; cuid4074 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - [Bassano del Grappa], undated; cuid4075 (Box Oversize, Folder 342)
        Oversize, V.B.2.3. folder 342.
      - Brescia, undated; cuid4076 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Brescia: Santa Maria dei Miracoli, undated; cuid4077 (Box 3, Folder 10a.)
      - Camugliano (province of Pisa), undated; cuid4078 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Lucca, undated; cuid4079 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Modena: Palazzo Ducale, undated; cuid4080 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Napoli, 1916; cuid4081 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        Print taken on an Acton family trip, 1916
      - Napoli, undated; cuid4082 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Napoli [La Quiete, the 'Vesuvian villa' of Donna Giulia Betocchi, mother of Clotilde Marghieri], undated; cuid4083 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        See "More Memoirs of an Aesthete". Print by G. Parisio, Napoli, with a dedication to HA on the verso.
      - Paestum, undated; cuid4084 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        Photos by Brogi, 5134.
      - Palermo, Giardino Botanico, undated; cuid4085 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        Photo by Brogi, 10831
      - Perugia, undated; cuid4086 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Pietrasanta, 1903; cuid4087 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Pompeii, undated; cuid4088 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        Photo by Cav. Arch. Mauri, Napoli.
      - Rocca di Papa (province of Roma), undated; cuid4089 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        Photo by Brogi, 16949.
      - Roma, the Roman Forum, 1916; cuid4090 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Roma, the Roman Forum, undated; cuid4091 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        Photo by Brogi, 3643.
      - Roma, the view from outside Villa Medici on the Pincio, undated; cuid4092 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Roma, Teatro di Marcello, undated; cuid4093 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        Annotated on the verso "Circus Marcello, Palazzo Sermoneta: window on left our apartment spooky looking".
      - Roma, Palazzo Massimo, undated; cuid4094 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        Photo by Brogi, 8793.
      - Roma, a religious ceremony on the steps of Santa Maria in Aracoeli, undated; cuid4095 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Roma, Palazzo Cardelli, undated; cuid4096 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        Photo by R. Moscioni, Roma, 21846.
      - Roma, undated; cuid4097 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Roma, Vatican gardens, undated; cuid4098 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Ronciglione (province of Viterbo), undated; cuid4099 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        Photo by R. Moscioni, Roma, 22016.
      - San Gimignano (province of Siena), ca. 1920; cuid4100 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Siena, undated; cuid4101 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Tarquinia, undated; cuid4102 (Box 3, Folder 35)
        Photo by Brogi, 9271.
      - Tivoli, Tempio della Sibilla, undated; cuid4103 (Box 3, Folder 36)
        #1. photo by Ernesto Richter, Roma, 10022.
      - Venezia, undated; cuid4104 (Box 3, Folder 37)
        Photo by Brogi, 13234.
      - Viterbo, undated; cuid4105 (Box 3, Folder 38)
        3. Photo by R. Moscioni, Roma, 3454.
      - Viterbo, undated; cuid4106 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Zagarolo (province of Roma), undated; cuid4107 (Box 3, Folder 40)
        Photo by R. Moscioni, 20343.
    - 3 Europe
      - Belgium: Chateau de Tourronde (the residence of the Duchesse de Vendome), undated; cuid4108 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - France: Gorges du Tarn, undated; cuid4109 (Box 3, Folder 42)
        Prints by A. Trantoul, Toulouse
      - France: Orsay (Essonne), ca. 1987; cuid4110 (Box 3, Folder 43)
        The residence of Diana Mosley, née Mitford, 1987. Color print used as a Christmas card by Diana Mosley to HA, annotated on the verso.
      - France: Sutry (between Vevey and Lausanne), undated; cuid4111 (Box 3, Folder 44)
        Annotated on the verso by AA "taken by my friend McCann with a Leica…".
      - France: Chateau d'Hauteville, Vevey, including an interior, undated; cuid4112 (Box 3, Folder 45)
        3. and 4. a garden temple very similar to the Tempietto in the gardens of Villa La Pietra, annotated on the verso by AA.
      - France: Chenonçeaux, undated; cuid4113 (Box Missing Value, Folder Missing Value)
        Photo by C. Peigné, Tours.
      - Chateau de Blois, undated; cuid4114 (Box Missing Value, Folder Missing Value)
        Photo by ND.
      - France: Chateau de Chantilly, undated; cuid4115 (Box Oversize, Folder 343)
        Oversize, V.B.3.3. folder 343.
      - Germany: Berlin: the destruction of the monument to King Friedrich Wilhelm IV in the Second World War, undated; cuid4116 (Box 3, Folder 46)
        Photo by Carl Weinrother, Berlin.
      - Germany: Schloss Sanssouci (Potsdam), undated; cuid4117 (Box 3, Folder 46a.)
      - Great Britain: Aldenham Estate, undated; cuid4118 (Box 3, Folder 47)
        From a sale catalogue of Christie, Manson and Woods Ltd.
      - Great Britain: Clinton Lodge, undated; cuid4119 (Box 3, Folder 48)
        Property of L. Einstein.
      - Great Britain: Clovelly, undated; cuid4120 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Great Britain: Colets Well, Otford, Kent, undated; cuid4121 (Box 3, Folder 49a.)
        The property of Helen Maclean (on a printed New Year's card from Helen Maclean).
      - Great Britain: [Colets Well, Otford, Kent, the property of Helen Maclean], undated; cuid4122 (Box 3, Folder 49b.)
        On a greeting card, printed on the recto: "Love from Helen".
      - Great Britain: Garsington, near Oxford, 1990; cuid4123 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Great Britain: Hove, undated; cuid4124 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Great Britain: Wixenford, Berks, undated; cuid4125 (Box 3, Folder 52)
        The preparatory school attended by HA 1912-1916, also interiors.
      - Great Britain: Yester House, Gifford, East Lothian, undated; cuid4126 (Box 3, Folder 53)
        17th century house restyled in the 18th century by Robert Adam, and purchased by Gian Carlo Menotti in 1972.
      - Greece: Athens, undated; cuid4127 (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Spain: Burgos, undated; cuid4128 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - Spain: Santiago, undated; cuid4129 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - Spain: [Madrid], undated; cuid4130 (Box Oversize, Folder 344)
        Oversize, V.B.3.3. folder 344.
      - Spain, 1966; cuid4131 (Box 3, Folder 57)
        Color prints taken in 1966 on a trip by HA and Alexander Zielcke.
      - Spain, ca. 1965; cuid4132 (Box 3, Folder 57a.)
        Color negs. taken in 1965 or 1966 on a trip by HA and Alexander Zielcke.
    - 4 US
      - Beaumont, California: the Edward-Dean Museum of Decorative Arts, ca. 1958; cuid4133 (Box 3, Folder 58)
        Created by Edward Eberle who lived here with Guy Mitchell, brother of HMA. Color prints annotated on the verso by Eberle.
      - Ipswich, Mass: Castle Hill, ca. 1924; cuid4134 (Box 3, Folder 59)
        Residence of Florence and Richard Crane: their second house built ca. 1924.
      - Ipswich, Mass: Castle Hill, ca. 1924; cuid4135 (Box 3, Folder 60)
        Residence of Florence and Richard Crane: their first house built ca. 1910 and demolished ca. 1924.
      - Ipswich, Mass: Castle Hill, ca. 1920s; cuid4136 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - Ipswich, Mass: Castle Hill, undated; cuid4137 (Box 3, Folder 62)
        Residence of Florence and Richard Crane. The 'Grand Allèe' on the Atlantic.
      - Ipswich, Mass: Castle Hill, ca. 1920s; cuid4138 (Box 3, Folder 62a.)
        Residence of Florence and Richard Crane. The garden and herbaceous border.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, undated; cuid4139 (Box 3, Folder 63)
        Residence of Louise and Walter Dillingham, cousins of HMA. Architectural drawings by David Adler, annotated on the verso by Louise Dillingham.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, undated; cuid4140 (Box 3, Folder 64)
        Residence of Louise and Walter Dillingham, cousins of HMA. See also III.A.8.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, undated; cuid4141 (Box 3, Folder 65)
        Residence of Louise and Walter Dillingham, cousins of HMA. Photos by Post, annotated on the verso by Louise Dillingham.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, undated; cuid4142 (Box 3, Folder 66)
        Residence of Louise and Walter Dillingham, cousins of HMA. Color print.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, undated; cuid4143 (Box 3, Folder 67)
        Residence of Louise and Walter Dillingham, cousins of HMA.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, 1956; cuid4144 (Box 3, Folder 68)
        Residence of Louise and Walter Dillingham, cousins of HMA. Color prints.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu: Villa La Pietra, undated; cuid4145 (Box 3, Folder 69)
      - Hawaii, Honolulu, undated; cuid4146 (Box 3, Folder 70)
        Photos by R.J. Baker.
      - Hawaii, Honolulu, undated; cuid4147 (Box 3, Folder 71)
        Photos by Williams Studio.
      - Magnolia, Mass.: Lee Cottage, 1921; cuid4148 (Box 3, Folder 72)
        Rented for the summer in 1921 by Marguerite Sheriff née Mitchell (sister of HMA). See also IV.C.3.25.27.-1.
      - [The Trianon], Colorado Springs, residence of Charles and Virginia Baldwin, 1921; cuid4149 (Box Oversize, Folder 345)
        Sketches for the design were made by Stanford White before his death in 1905.
        Annotated on the recto "Baldwin Home" (mounted prints of exteriors and interiors).
        Oversize, V.B.4.3. folder 345.
    - 5 rest of the world
      - Azores: Horta, undated; cuid4150 (Box 3, Folder 73)
        Where HA was stationed briefly during the Second World War.
      - Egypt, including people in street scenes, undated; cuid4151 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Egypt: Assuan dam, undated; cuid4152 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - India: military scenes and general, including people, undated; cuid4153 (Box 3, Folder 76)
        Taken by HA who was stationed here in the Second World War.
      - India: mountain scenes, undated; cuid4154 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      - India: Amber, undated; cuid4155 (Box Oversize, Folder 346)
        Formerly Umber. Photos by Clifton and Co. Mounted by Linotype, Gautier, Paris.
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 346.
      - India: Agra, undated; cuid4156 (Box Oversize, Folder 347)
        Photos by Clifton and Co. Mounted by Linotype, Gautier, Paris.
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 347.
      - India: Benhares (now Varanasi), undated; cuid4157 (Box Oversize, Folder 348)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 348.
      - India: Delhi, undated; cuid4158 (Box Oversize, Folder 349)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 349.
      - India: Futtehpore Sikri (now Fatehpur Sikri), undated; cuid4159 (Box Oversize, Folder 350)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 350.
      - India: Jeypore, undated; cuid4160 (Box Oversize, Folder 351)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 351.
      - India: Secundra, undated; cuid4161 (Box Oversize, Folder 352)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 352.
      - Japan: Naguya (tea house), undated; cuid4162 (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Japan: Chuzenji, undated; cuid4163 (Box Oversize, Folder 353)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 353.
      - Japan: Hakone, undated; cuid4164 (Box Oversize, Folder 354)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 354.
      - Japan: Kamakura, undated; cuid4165 (Box Oversize, Folder 355)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 355.
      - Japan: Kyoto, undated; cuid4166 (Box Oversize, Folder 356)
        Photos by Clifton and Co., mounted by Linotype, Gautier, Paris.
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 356.
      - Japan: Nikko, undated; cuid4167 (Box Oversize, Folder 357)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 357.
      - Japan: Osaka, undated; cuid4168 (Box Oversize, Folder 358)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 358.
      - Japan: Tokaido, undated; cuid4169 (Box Oversize, Folder 359)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 359.
      - Japan: Tokyo, undated; cuid4170 (Box Oversize, Folder 360)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 360.
      - Myanmar (formerly Burma), undated; cuid4171 (Box Oversize, Folder 361)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 361.
      - Japan: Yokohama, Grand Hotel, undated; cuid4172 (Box 3, Folder 78a.)
        See also I.B.2.4.-194. and 195.
      - Libya, Tripoli: Villa Volpi at Sciara sidi i khalifa., ca. 1957; cuid4173 (Box 3, Folder 79)
        Volpi was governor of Tripoli, and HA stayed here in 1957 with his daughters Anna Maria Cicogna and Marina Luling (who also owned Villa Maser in the Veneto in Italy). Includes an interior.
      - Mexico, 1947; cuid4174 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - 6 unidentified
      - [Italy], undated; cuid4175 (Box 3, Folder 81)
      - [Italy: Ischia], undated; cuid4176 (Box 3, Folder 82)
      - [Italy: Mantova], undated; cuid4177 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      - [Italy: olive trees], undated; cuid4178 (Box 3, Folder 83a.)
        3 attached photos.
      - [Italy: a road through a pine forest], undated; cuid4179 (Box 3, Folder 83b.)
      - Italy: a loggia [Siena], undated; cuid4180 (Box 3, Folder 83c.)
      - Italy: a palace with an outside stair and courtyard, undated; cuid4181 (Box 3, Folder 83d.)
      - [Italy: Roma], ca. 1960; cuid4182 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      - [Italy: war photographs], undated; cuid4183 (Box 3, Folder 85)
      - [Italy: war photographs], undated; cuid4184 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      - Italy: a convent hermitage, undated; cuid4185 (Box 3, Folder 86a.)
      - [France], undated; cuid4186 (Box 3, Folder 87)
      - [France: a villa in Paris], undated; cuid4187 (Box 3, Folder 88)
        Annotated on the verso by HMA "owned by Vittorio Bourbon's sister".
      - [France], undated; cuid4188 (Box Oversize, Folder 362)
        Oversize, V.B.6.3. folder 362.
      - [GB,London], undated; cuid4189 (Box 3, Folder 88a.)
      - [GB], undated; cuid4190 (Box 3, Folder 89)
      - [GB], undated; cuid4191 (Box 3, Folder 89a.)
        Annotated on the verso "Trenarren Ho. 1805". Color print.
      - [GB] a garden with a portico and a pool, undated; cuid4192 (Box 3, Folder 90)
        Annotated on the recto [Melchet Park, Wiltshire].
      - [US] country houses, undated; cuid4193 (Box 3, Folder 91)
        Landscapes. 14. and 15. negs.
      - [US] residence, undated; cuid4194 (Box 3, Folder 92)
        Annotated on the verso by HMA "Carrie's house".
      - Misfiled, no photo, undated; cuid4195 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - [Azores] a native dance, undated; cuid4196 (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - [Egypt: Cairo], undated; cuid4197 (Box Oversize, Folder 363)
        Oversize, V.B.6.3. folder 363.
      - [India] a statue of an elephant, undated; cuid4198 (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - [India] an ocean liner with sailors [and prisoners], 1901; cuid4199 (Box 3, Folder 95a.)
        Annotated on the verso "Empress of India, August 1901" [the liner which was launched in 1890 at Barrow, and used by Canadian Pacific for regular transpacific services from Vancouver to Hong Kong with calls at Yokohama, Kobe, Nagasaki and Shanghai. In 1914 she was converted into an Indian Army hospital ship before being broken up in Bombay in 1923].
      - [India] a radio broadcast by the Army Publicity Department (in an interior), undated; cuid4200 (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - [India, Japan, Myanmar], undated; cuid4201 (Box Oversize, Folder 364)
        Oversize, V.B.5.3. folder 364.
- Series VI: Postcards
  - Subseries A: Places (exteriors)
    - 1 Firenze
      - Firenze, undated; cuid4202 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Firenze, ca. 1918; cuid4203 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2 Italy
      - Alberobello (province of Bari), undated; cuid4204 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Amalfi, undated; cuid4205 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Andria (province of Bari), undated; cuid4206 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Assisi (province of Perugia), undated; cuid4207 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Capri (province of Napoli), undated; cuid4208 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Certaldo (province of Firenze), undated; cuid4209 (Box 1, Folder 7a.)
      - Figline Val d'Arno (province of Firenze), undated; cuid4210 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Ischia (province of Napoli), undated; cuid4211 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Isola Farnese (province of Roma), undated; cuid4212 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Mantova, undated; cuid4213 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Modena, undated; cuid4214 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Monreale (province of Palermo), undated; cuid4215 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Monte Oliveto Maggiore (province of Siena), undated; cuid4216 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Napoli, undated; cuid4217 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Orta San Giulio (province of Novara), undated; cuid4218 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Padova, ca. 1914; cuid4219 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Paestum (province of Salerno), undated; cuid4220 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Palermo, undated; cuid4221 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Parma, undated; cuid4222 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Perugia, undated; cuid4223 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Pienza (province of Siena), undated; cuid4224 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Pistoia, undated; cuid4225 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Poppi (province of Arezzo), undated; cuid4226 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Posillipo (province of Napoli), undated; cuid4227 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        Annotated on the recto by HA "the house below me".
      - Possagno (province of Treviso), undated; cuid4228 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Pozzuoli (province of Napoli), undated; cuid4229 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Riva del Garda (province of Trento), undated; cuid4230 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Roma, undated; cuid4231 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - I Ronchi (province of Massa Carrara), undated; cuid4232 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - San Gimignano (province of Siena), undated; cuid4233 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - San Gimignano, Pieve di Cellole (province of Siena), undated; cuid4234 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - San Leo (province of Urbino), undated; cuid4235 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - San Marino, undated; cuid4236 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Sorrento (province of Napoli), undated; cuid4237 (Box 1, Folder 35)